Guide to the Charles S. Ascher Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Manuscripts, Documents and Course Material
  - NAHRO - International Committee - Documents, 1963-1965 (Box 122)
  - NAHRO - International Committee - New, 1975-1976 (Box 122)
  - NAHRO - International Committee - Meetings (numbered, 27-32) (Box 122)
  - NAHRO - International Committee - Meetings (numbered, 33-41) (Box 123)
  - NAHRO - International Committee - Meetings (numbered, 14 (Box 123)
  - NAHRO - International Committee - Members (Box 123)
  - NAHRO - Joint Committee of Housing and Health (Box 123)
  - NAHRO - New York Metropolitan Chapter (Box 123)
  - National Association of School of Public Affairs and Administration (NASPAA) 1970-75 (Box 123)
  - NASPAA, 1975-1978 (Box 125)
  - National Capital Park and Planning Commission (Box 125)
  - National Housing Agency (Box 125)
  - National Management Council (Box 125)
  - National Planning Association (Box 125)
  - National Resources Planning Board (Box 125)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation (Box 125)
  - New York City - Civil Service Commission (Box 125)
  - New York City - Convention and Visitors Bureau (American Congress on Inter­national Meetings) (Box 126)
  - York City:
    - Health Institute (Box 126)
    - Mayor’s Committee for Better Housing (Box 126)
    - Tokyo - Sister City (Box 126)
    - Volunteers (Box 126)
  - New York State - Health Department (Box 126)
  - Non-Governmental Organizations [U.N.] (NGOs) - General, 1948-1952 (Box 126)
  - NGOs:
    - General, 1953-1957 (Box 127)
    - General, 1960-1979 (Box 128)
    - Bureau, 1953-1959 (Box 128)
    - Bureau, 1960-1973 (Box 129)
    - Conferences, General, 1960-1966 (Box 129)
    - Conferences, General, 1969-1972 (Box 130)
    - Development Committee (Box 130)
    - ECOSOC - General (Box 130)
    - ECOSOC - Review of NGOs (Box 130)
    - Human Environment (Box 130)
    - Human Rights (Box 131)
    - Lists of NGOs (Box 131)
    - Review of Status, 1965-1968 (Box 131)
    - U Thant Lunch (Box 131)
    - Working Group on Science and Technology (Box 131)
  - Organization of American States/Pan American Union (Box 132)
  - Pacific-Asian Conference of Municipalities (PACOM) (Box 132)
  - Park-Hudson Urban Renewal Citizens’ Committee - General, 1959 (Box 132)
  - Park-Hudson Urban Renewal Citizens’ Committee - Association of Neighborhood Councils (Box 132)
  - Park-Hudson Urban Renewal Citizens’ Committee - Background (Box 132)
  - Park-Hudson Urban Renewal Citizens’ Committee: (Box 133)
    - Correspondence (Box 133)
    - Funds (Box 133)
    - Housing and Redevelopment Boar (Box 133)
    - Meetings (Box 133)
    - Staff (Box 133)
    - Statements (Box 133)
    - West Side Story (Box 133)
  - Pre-School Association of the West Side (Box 133)
  - Public Administration Clearing House (PACH) – General, 1931-1956 (Box 133)
  - PACH:
    - Annual Reports, 1949-1954 (Box 134)
    - Dinner, U.N., 1950 (Box 134)
    - Dinner Talk, 1951 (Box 134)
    - Financial (Box 134)
    - International Program (Box 134)
    - Reception, 1950 (Box 134)
    - Round-ups (Box 134)
  - Regional Plan Association (Box 135)
  - Royal Institute of Public Administration (Box 135)
  - Snag Club (Box 135)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) - General, 1937 19U8-1971 (Box 135)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) - Correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 135)
  - SSRC - Correspondence (Box 136)
  - SSRC - Committee on Housing Research (Box 136)
  - SSRC - Committee on Public Administration (see also SSRC Correspondence) (Box 136)
  - Sociedad Interamericana de Planificacion (SIAP) - 1958-1960 (Box 136)
  - SIAP – 1961-1970 (Box 137)
  - SIAP - 1971-1977 (Box 138)
  - Society for International Development (SID) (Box 138)
  - State, U.S. Department of (Foreign Service) (Box 138)
  - Stycker's Bay Neighborhood Council (Box 138)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) (Box 138)
  - Town and Country Planning Association (U.K.) (Box 138)
  - Twentieth Congressional District, N.Y. - Conferences (Box 138)
  - Union of International Associations (UIA) (Box 139)
  - United Nations (UN):
    - General Correspondence and miscellaneous items (Box 139)
    - Africa (Box 139)
    - Asia (Box 139)
    - Children's Fund (UNICEF) (Box 139)
    - Conference on Science and Technology for Development (UNCSTJJD (Box 139)
  - UN:
    - Development Program (Box 140)
    - ESCAP (Box 140)
    - Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC) (Box 140)
    - Economic Rights and Duties of States (Box 140)
    - Environmental Program (UNEP):
      - Governing Council (Box 140)
      - North American NGO Council (Box 140)
      - Stockholm, 1972 (Box 140)
    - Habitat (Box 141)
    - Housing, Building and Planning Centre, 1961f-1975 (Box 141)
    - Human Rights (Box 141)
    - Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR) (Box 142)
    - International Women’s Year (Box 142)
    - International Year of the Child (Box 142)
    - Meetings, Seminars and Symposia, 1966-1979 and miscellaneous (Box 142)
    - New Towns - Delhi Conference, 1960 (Box 142)
    - New Towns - Moscow Conference (Box 143)
    - New Towns - London Conference, 1973 (Box 143)
    - Office of Public Information (Box 144)
    - Public Administration Division - General (Box 144)
    - Public Administration Division - Evaluation (Box 144)
    - Public Administration Division - Experts, 1970-1971 (Box 144)
    - Public Administration Division - Experts, 1975 (Box 145)
    - Research Institute for Social Development (Box 145)
    - World Population Year, 1974 (Box 145)
    - World University (Box 145)
  - UNESCO:
    - General Correspondence and Notes (Box 145)
    - Ascher, Charles S.- job (Box 145)
    - Budget (Box 146)
    - Conference Techniques, 1948-1950 (Box 146)
    - Conference Techniques, 1950-1951 (Box 147)
    - Constitution (Box 147)
    - Documents, Miscellaneous, 1945-197O (Box 147)
    - Ebenstein Correspondence (Box 147)
    - Executive Board (Box 147)
    - Financial (Box 147)
    - General Conferences, 1946-1948 (Box 148)
    - History (Box 148)
    - Mercury (UNESCO Staff Publication) (Box 148)
    - Programme, 1947-1949 (Box 149)
    - Programme-making, 1948-1952 (Box 150)
    - Social Sciences (Box 150)
    - Survey Article (Box 150)
    - Association of the USA (Box 150)
    - U.S. (Box 150)
    - National Commission for UNESCO (Box 150)
    - U.S. (Box 150)
    - Department of State (Box 150)
    - Urbanization (Box 150)
    - Printed and miscellaneous material (Box 150)
  - United States - Civil Service Commission (Box 15l)
  - Federal Executive Seminars (Box 15l)
  - Senate (Box 15l)
  - United Towns Organization (Box 15l)
  - West Side Chamber of Commerce (Box 15l)
  - White House Conference on Balanced National Growth and Economic Development (Box 15l)
  - World Environment and Resources Council (Box 15l)
  - World Federation for Mental Health (WFMH) - General, 19U7-I955 (Box 15l)
  - World Federation for Mental Health: (Box 152)
    - General, 1968-1979 (Box 152)
    - Ascher, Helen - Fund (Box 152)
    - Caribbean Federation of Mental Health (Box 152)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace Seminar (Box 152)
  - World Health Organization (WHO) - General, 19U6-1979 (Box 152)
  - WHO:
    - Coordination (Box 153)
    - Decentralization (Box 153)
    - Director General - memos (Box 153)
    - Directors’ Committee minutes (Box 153)
    - ECOSOC (Box 153)
    - Financial (Box 153)
    - Interviews (Box 153)
    - Notes, Study (Box 153)
    - Smith, R. (Box 153)
    - Survey Article (Box 153)
    - Technical Discussions (Box 153)
    - Training (Box 154)
    - U.S. (Box 154)
  - World Peace Foundation (Box 154)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations - Conferences (Box 154)
- Series IV: Travel (includes photographs)
  - General, 1947-1951 (Box 154)
  - General, 1953-1959 (Box 155)
  - General, 1960-I962 (Box 156)
  - General, 1963-1964 (Box 157)
  - Itineraries (Box 157)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 157)
  - Asia (Box 158)
  - Brazil (Box 158)
  - Caribbean (Box 158)
  - Europe, 1951-1957 (Box 158)
  - Europe, 1958-1977 (Box 159)
  - Switzerland (Box 159)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 160)
  - Awards (Box 160)
  - Photos (Box 160)
  - Printed - Clippings (Box 160)
  - Printed - Miscellaneous (Box 160)
  - Inscribed books (Box 161)
- Series V: Oversize
  - 1 volume - clippings (Box 162)
  - 1 volume - Gateway National Recreation Area Study (Box 163)
  - Posters, Maps and Plans (rolls) - 11 (shelved at end of collection) (Box 163)